<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: GitHub Pages | dev.tony]]></title>
  <link href="http://tonyferrell.github.io/blog/categories/github-pages/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tonyferrell.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-05T01:54:38-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tonyferrell.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tony Ferrell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blogging! Octopress!]]></title>
    <link href="http://tonyferrell.github.io/blog/2014/04/04/blogging-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-04T21:58:40-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tonyferrell.github.io/blog/2014/04/04/blogging-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Note: Since I don&rsquo;t have any of the appropriate boilerplate/about in place yet &ndash; I work for Microsoft, and this blog is my own thoughts, not anyone elses.</em></p>

<p>Turns out I&rsquo;m not particularly good at writing stuff down. This blog is my effort to change that.</p>

<h2>Why Octopress</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;m a pretty technical person &ndash; on average I probably spend 20+ hours a week writing code (lucky me, I know!) for Microsoft, or personal prjects, and it would be really easy for me to get sucked into writing a blogging platform (or starting to writing a blogging platform, and get tired of it), and never actually, you know, do any blogging. I knew when I started out that I needed a simple, lightweight platform to blog on. While I&rsquo;ve done a considerable amount of development for WordPress, and I&rsquo;ve checked out platforms like Ghost, I knew I wanted something even simpler Realistically, I wanted a solution that was simple for me to setup, but easy enough to move to what I wanted later.</p>

<p>Enter <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>. I knew I was going to host on github pages (or some git backed platform), so I tried a couple of custom solutions (grunt + jade etc.) After an evening of exploration, I realized I was getting sucked down the &ldquo;tech blackhole&rdquo; and decided I couldn&rsquo;t invest that much more time in scaffolding my own stuff. So at the suggestion of my good friend <a href="http://willi.am">Willi.am</a>, and after being assured that installing ruby on Windows wasn&rsquo;t as painful as it used to be, I decided to give it a shot.</p>

<p>The main problem that octopress solves (in my mind &ndash; I understand that it has other benefits) is that GitHub pages require that the content be static &ndash; which means that if you want anything more than a little complex, everything has to be generated offline. It also provides a fairly complete scaffold, so I can start generating content quickly.</p>

<p>I also appreciate that I can write all of my content in markdown &ndash; markdown isn&rsquo;t my favorite way to write prettier text (yet?), but it&rsquo;s simple, functional, and can be easily versioned. That means that I can accept pull requests from people who find issues/want to contribute to my content. It also means that if I move to another platform that accepts markdown, I&rsquo;m pretty much set. (It&rsquo;s also easy to just render to html and keep it that way, if I need to.)</p>

<h2>Going Forward</h2>

<p>Eventually, I hope to revisit other systems &ndash; honestly, I&rsquo;m not particularly enthusiastic about using ruby. Nothing against it, it&rsquo;s just another tool, and I don&rsquo;t really have any projects in mind for it, and I&rsquo;m not currently using it for any other projects. Realistically, I&rsquo;d much rather be building on <a href="http://nodejs.org">nodejs</a>, since that&rsquo;s where I&rsquo;m looking to broaden my current skills.</p>

<p>The site still has a ways to go technically &ndash; if nothing else, I need to actually do some styling (what, you don&rsquo;t <em>love</em> the default theme?!) and figure out getting comments enabled. Content wise, I should write a little bit about myself (so I can read it when I forget), and generate some real content. Going forward I hope to have a mix of technical, and &ldquo;professional&rdquo; posts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
